<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Software Development on First Law of Robotics</title><link>https://firstlaw.io/tags/software-development/</link><description>Recent content in Software Development on First Law of Robotics</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 14:10:21 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://firstlaw.io/tags/software-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is the difference between middle and senior developer?</title><link>https://firstlaw.io/posts/mid-senior-dev/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 14:10:21 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://firstlaw.io/posts/mid-senior-dev/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Software development is not just a profession; it&amp;rsquo;s an art, a science, and a journey. At different stages of this journey, we find ourselves with varying levels of expertise and problem-solving skills. A frequent question that comes up is, what sets a senior developer apart from a middle-level developer? The answer may surprise you: It&amp;rsquo;s less about the code you write and more about the problems you solve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="defining-roles"&gt;Defining Roles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Middle Developers: Generally, middle developers are proficient in coding and can build features, fix bugs, and understand the project at a reasonable depth. They are essential team members who contribute significantly to the codebase.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>What is RFCs and how to use them</title><link>https://firstlaw.io/posts/rfc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 14:10:21 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://firstlaw.io/posts/rfc/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today my colleague shared that they started to use RFCs inside of their development team. I was surprised in a way that I thought &amp;ldquo;why it&amp;rsquo;s not a common practice?&amp;rdquo;. I know that it&amp;rsquo;s not a common practice because I never used it in my previous companies. But I think it&amp;rsquo;s a good practice and I want to share it with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-is-rfc"&gt;What is RFC?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RFC stands for Request for Comments. It&amp;rsquo;s a document that describes a new feature or a change to the existing system. It should describe a problem and proposed solution. It&amp;rsquo;s used to discuss the change with the team and to get feedback from the team.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>